

A Montreal based full-stack developer crafting applications and services in Javascript

In a nutshell

I am a full-stack staff developer who has worn many hats and worked with many teams of all sizes to build applications and services for a wide range of organizations including startups, not-for-profits, and fortune 500 companies.

I have been known to <u>contribute</u> to <u>open source</u>, write about <u>technology</u>, experiment with <u>home automation</u>, and advocate for <u>cord-cutting</u>. I like to build things like my SaaS product <u>publier</u>, or my AppleTV app <u>OverseerrTV</u>.

Technology focus

HTML	CSS	Javas	cript	Typescript		Node.js		NestJS	React	R	eact Native
MySQL	Mon	goDB	Jest	Git	Docker		Google Cloud		Firebase		Terraform
Prometheus		Grafana	a								

Career

Open Source Consultant

Nov 2023 - Present

As an Open Source Consultant, I partnered with not-for-profit organizations to implement tailored solutions using the Formulize project (formulize.org). My contributions included integrating end-to-end testing, establishing robust logging and monitoring systems, and enhancing accessibility compliance. These efforts significantly improved software reliability, operational oversight, and user inclusivity for my non-profit clients.

Staff Software Engineer and Technical Lead @ ecobee

Mar 2017 - Nov 2023

I started as a senior developer and quickly moved to a staff position. I have been the technical lead for two teams and have helped launch four recurring revenue subscription products <a href="ecobee-background-cobe-backgr

I led the design and development of the underlying scalable microservice architecture for most of these products and the integration with multiple partner platforms.

Software Engineer @ Acquia

Sept 2015 - Mar 2017

I joined the Acquia Cloud UI team building production-ready components in vanilla Javascript and AngularJS to support the beta launch of the new Cloud UI product. I later joined the Acquia Lift team. I was one of two frontend developers that designed, built, and launched the next-generation Acquia Lift frontend application.

Web Developer @ Myplanet

Nov 2011 - Sept 2015

- Unofficially the Ronin developer moving from project to project where needed to help different teams to meet critical deadlines.
- Lead developer on multiple prototyping engagements in both Drupal and Javascript.
- I developed an internal communication tool in my spare time which was adopted by the company and resulted in several open-source contributions.

Web Developer @ Freeform Solutions

Nov 2009 - Sept 2011

- Lead developer on many Drupal and CiviCRM projects for not-for-profit organizations.
- Led initiatives to introduce DevOps to the development teams to improve the developer experience.
- Due to the small team size, I wore many hats on different projects which included developer, scrum master, QA, designer, and technical account manager.

Hobbies

Since the start of the pandemic, I have taken up several non-tech-focused hobbies including solving a Rubik's cube, juggling, lockpicking, and card magic. Basically, everything I wanted to learn as a kid.

Education

University of Windsor

BSc, Computer Science 2000 – 2005